# **Ben Myers**

UCLA undergraduate pursuing B.S. in Mathematics with three years of customer service experience, one year of educational experience, and five years of programming experience. Involved in software development, management, and business growth.

Personal involvements include UCLA Chorale, UCLA Sigma Eta Pi, Bruin Entrepreneurs, and the UCLA Founder's Club. Interests include AI; cryptocurrency; proof computation; DJ'ing; music/video production; choral singing; VC.

benl.myers01@gmail.com benlmyers.com

+1 561-374-4627 github.com/benlmyers

## Skills

# Languages

Swift, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C++, C#, Python, Rust, Processing

### **Environments and Tools**

SwiftUI, UIKit, React, React Native, Vue, Vite, Java, Git, Github, Blender, Unity, Unreal Engine

# **Education**

Alexander W. Dreyfoos School of the Arts H.S. Diploma, 2020 | 4.0 GPA | 5.037 HPA | 1510 SAT | 33 ACT

University of California, Los Angeles B.S. Mathematics, 2024 | 3.483 Major GPA

# **Experience**

## **Co-Founder and CTO**

Jun 2022 - Present www.joinpoppin.com

Poppin Technologies - Full-time

- Scaled user-base by 9,700% from 72 to 7,000 MAU with 500+ organic user-hosted events, breaking Top 100 on App Store.
- Improved day-by-day retention to 17% / 10% / 6% with dynamic content/linking, payment integration, and social features.
- · Reduced web/mobile development costs by 80% from \$1,000 to \$200/mo. by leading a team of 5 and optimizing app costs.

#### Founder and CEO Jan 2021 - Present

Flowductive - Part-time

www.flowductive.com

- · Self-built 5 iterations of an iOS + macOS productivity app; web landing page; and 3 companion open-source Swift packages.
- · Single-handedly managed, produced content, and raised socials to 650+ LinkedIn followers and 120+ Instagram followers.
- · Built and managed an internship cohort of 18; sourced 40 investors; captured attention of industry-leading VC's, raising \$5,000.

### **Technical Growth Analyst**

Nov 2020 - Present

Yatco - Full-time

www.yatco.com

- · Performed an SEO analysis for a yachting MLS website with 600+ visitors/day in traffic, organizing 300+ builder pages.
- Parsed data from 2000+ yacht builder sites into JSON using Python for site use, raising CTR by 0.4% over 3 months.
- Developed mobile Charter/Consumer application expected to transition 150k total web users to 730k mobile users per year.

#### iOS Developer Dec 2021 - Feb 2022

Edvora - Internship

www.edvora.com

- · Stabilized and widened the mobile device compatibility of a global SaaS education solution by implementing SwiftUI in iPadOS.
- · Improved the quality and scalability of the future of Ed-tech in education, technology, finance, and enterprise through patches in Jira.

# **Projects**

### **Predictive LSTM Model on AAPL**

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

Stock Price Predictor in Python

https://bit.ly/3FJcOG5

- · Wrote a Long-Short-Term-Memory ML model in Python and Colab to predict future closing prices of MSFT, AAPL, and AMC.
- · Visualized findings using both PyTorch and TensorFlow to analyze fit accuracy, margins of error, and quantitative predictions.
- Reduced the model's mean absolute error during testing by 15.2% by reducing short-term memory by 50% from 6 to 3 days.

## Dezeus Automated Proof Solver in Java

Jan 2021 - Present

https://github.com/benlmyers/dezeus-gamma · Created three iterations of a model used to prove mathematical or logical statements to any level of rigor with 100% accuracy.

- · Used Java to classify propositional statements and zeroth-order logic for symbolization, derivation, and theorem application.
- · Built a robust rule management system with custom file types to save and restore logical propositions for scalable use online.

# Swift Packages Front-End, Open-Source in Swift

Nov 2020 - Present

https://bit.ly/3v8ZXHa

- · Wrote over 350 commits in 7 solo open-source packages, actively maintained, organically earning over 75 stars on Github.
- · EasyFirebase, one package, used advanced Swift syntax to reduce database and service complexity of Google Firebase products.
- · ShinySwiftUI, one package, used SwiftUI to create common interface components with consistent layout and appearance.